Guide to the Elizabeth and Felix G. Rohatyn Papers Circa 1900?-2020 (bulk 1975-2012) MS 3015
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Elizabeth Rohatyn Board Files, 1993-2013; 3 Linear feet
  - Subseries V.A. French Regional & American Museum Exchange (FRAME), 1999-2012; 1.33 Linear feet
    FRAME initially operated under the auspices of the Foundation for French Museums. In 2006, FRAME incorporated itself as a not-for-profit organization in the United States. FRAME operates through two organizational arms, one in the U.S. and the other in France, each headed by a President and a Director. A Board of Trustees heads the overall organization. Starting from a membership of about 18 museums in 1999, the organization included 30 museums in its consortium as of 2017.
    FRAME has sponsored about 21 exhibitions since its founding. The first exhibition was Made in the USA: American Art from 1908-1947, which toured at three museums in France. Most of the exhibitions since then made stops at museums in both the U.S. and France.
    (The above note was based principally on FRAME's website http://www.framemuseums.org/en/ and from documents in the collection.)
    The subseries includes documentation concerning the founding and first decade of FRAME's operations. Among these documents are vision and mission statements, historical notes, membership lists, budgets and fundraising efforts, meeting agendas and summaries, press clippings, exhibition schedules and publicity, and correspondence and printed emails in connection with website development and other initiatives. The subseries includes documents related to the evolving nature of the organization in its first decade, including leadership changes, FRAME's incorporation as a not-for-profit entity, and by-law changes.
    The documents in the subseries remain in their original folders. These folders were compiled together in sets that are topically related (e.g., budgets, fundraising, meetings, etc.) and which advance in roughly chronological order.
    - FRAME Files (23 of 32 folders), 1999-2008 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1-23)
    - FRAME Files (9 of 32 folders), 2005-2012 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1-9)
  - Subseries V.B. Teaching Matters Inc. (TMI), 1993-2012; 0.67 Linear feet
    Originally known as The Waterford Institute, the organization was restructured in August 1994 and renamed Teaching Matters, Inc. (TMI). Elizabeth Rohatyn is credited as TMI's founder, and she was its first Chairman. A not-for-profit organization, TMI focused on the professional development of teachers and school administrators to enhance their effectiveness. In the early years of the organization this mission was expressed particularly in terms of assisting with the integration of technology into the school and classroom
    The TMI files include concept papers, Board meeting minutes and materials, early by-laws, mission statements and strategic plans, fundraising efforts, and budgets. There are also program proposals and reports, including an evaluation of TMI's One Laptop Per Child (OLPC) pilot program (2008), the McKinsey & Company's Connecting K-12 Schools to the Information Superhighway (1995), and TMI's first annual report (1995). There are a few files from TMI's earliest years in the mid-1990s, but most of the material dates from the 2000s. Coverage is inconsistent; for example, there are materials for only a few Board meetings in the 2000s. The subseries includes a folder of speeches given by Elizabeth from 1993-2000, not necessarily all concerning TMI. That same folder includes contact sheets of photographs of Elizabeth Rohatyn at an unidentified award ceremony and reception.
    The documents in the subseries remain in their original folders and are arranged by subject matter.
    - TMI Files (14 folders), 1993-2012 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10-23)
  - Subseries V.C. New York Public Library (NYPL), 2002-2013; 1 Linear feet
    Elizabeth Rohatyn served on NYPL's Board of Trustees from 1985, including as Chairman in 1996. The subseries includes various Board-level documents from the 2000s, though there is considerable inconsistency in the specific content. The subseries includes Board agendas, minutes, and meeting materials (2011, 2013); materials from various committees including the Executive (2004, 2011, 2013), Nominating (2003-2013), Budget (2002-2003), and Digital Strategy Committees (2007-2008); development strategies, fundraising and partnering efforts (2003-2011); and special initiatives including the Campaign for the Branch Libraries (2003-2005), a draft of McKinsey & Co.'s presentation on positioning the library for continuous improvement (2003), and the Virtual Library Task Force (2011-2012).
    - NYPL Files (25 folders), 2002-2013 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1-25)
- Series VI. Personal Photographs and Biographical Documents, Circa 1900?-2020; 2 Linear feet
  The series primarily includes personal photographs of Felix and Elizabeth Rohatyn and their parents, families, friends, associates, and others. Felix's early life is well-represented, including photographs of him as a child and young man in Europe, serving in the U.S. Army, skiing and doing other leisure activities, and with what appear to be business associates and his young family in the 1950s and 1960s. There are only a few early photographs of Elizabeth. There are many of Elizabeth and Felix from the years after their marriage in 1979, in casual settings such as vacations, at gala events, and at award ceremonies. In addition to photographs, there are a small number of other documents related to, especially, Felix, such as a copy of his birth certificate and employment application to Lazard. A small number of documents related to Rohatyn, post-mortem, were added to the papers.
  The series is arranged roughly by subject matter.
  - General Biographical Documents, 1929-1998 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    Includes original certified copies of Felix's birth certificate (1928, 1940); photocopies of visa (1941), certificate of naturalization (1950), and marriage certificate (1979); original employment application to Lazard (1948); tax return (1950); vaccination record (1958); photocopy of Elizabeth's birth certificate (1930); and other documents.
  - Notes on Ancestral Home of Rogatyn/Rohatyn, Poland, 1999, 2004 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Military (2 folders), 1951-1953 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Business (1 of 2 folders), 1967-1971 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    Includes a clipping concerning Rohatyn's election to the New York Stock Exchange (1968); photograph, clipping and page from annual report related to Rohatyn's position as Director on the Board of International Telephone & Telegraph Corporation (ITT) (1967-68); documents, in French, relating to a change in address for Societe Trannoy; and a few business cards.
  - Business (2 of 2 folders). New York Stock Exchange. Flat File, 1968 April 8 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
    Includes a poster listing the nominations, including Rohatyn, for positions on the NYSE.
  - Wyoming Home, 1995, 1997 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    Includes a bound copy of the issue of Architectural Digest featuring the Rohatyn's Wyoming home, and a map of the parcel.
  - Financial Matters (2 folders) (Restricted until 2030), 2001-2010 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8-9)
  - Artwork Inventory (Restricted until 2030), 2001 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degree from Columbia University (Felix), 2007 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
  - SIPA News. Notice of Harry Picker Award from Columbia University's School of International and Public Affairs (Felix), 2004 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
  - Program. Citizens Budget Commission's Inaugural Felix Rohatyn Award (Felix), 2017 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
  - Post Mortem, 2020 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9a)
    Scope and Contents
    Holds a small number of documents related to Rohatyn's death and memorial service.
  - Photograph Album. Inner-City Scholarship Fund Award Dinner. (Elizabeth & Felix), 1996 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
  - Photograph Album. City University of New York Graduate Center Benefit (Honoring Felix). Flat File, 2002 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
  - Photographs. City University of New York Award (Felix), Circa 1992? (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
  - Photographs. Rohatyns and Bill Clinton, 1990s (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photographs. Rohatyns and Hillary Clinton (inscribed), 2004 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photographs. Felix Rohatyn, Family, Friends, Associates (5 folders), Circa 1900?-1986 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4-8)
    The photographs in these folders are principally of Felix Rohatyn as a child, a young man, and into the 1970s. The photographs also include his parents from the 1930s (and perhaps earlier) into the mid-1980s, Rohatyn's children, and various unidentified family, friends, and associates.
  - Photographs. Elizabeth and Felix Rohatyn, Family, Friends, and Associates, 1955?-2010s (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9-15)
    These folders include some early photos of Elizabeth and her family (circa 1955?), snapshots at the Rohatyns wedding (1979), Felix receiving the French Legion of Honor award (1987), anniversary party for Forbes magazine (1987), Elizabeth with Brooke Astor (1990s?), at the embassy in Paris (by Marc Riboud), publicity material and clippings regarding Elizabeth's daughter, model Nina Griscom (1980s), clippings concerning social galas, including at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and other photographs.
  - Portrait Photograph of Felix Rohatyn by Bachrach. Flat File, 1970s? (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
  - Portrait Photograph of Felix Rohatyn by Richard Avedon. Flat File, 1976 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)